This is my first trip,
هذه رحلتي الأولى.
my first foreign trip as a first lady.
رحلتي الأولى الخارجية كسيدة أولى.
Can you believe that?
هل يمكنكم تصديق ذلك؟
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And while this is not my first visit to the U.K.,
وبينما هذه ليست رحلتي الأولى الى المملكة المتحدة،
I have to say that I am glad that this is my first official visit.
ينبغي عليّ القول أنني سعيدة لأن هذه أولى رحلاتي الرسمية.
The special relationship between the United States and the U.K.
العلاقة الخاصة بين الولايات المتحدة والمملكة المتحدة.
is based not only on the relationship between governments,
مبنية ليس فقط على العلاقة بين الحكومات،
but the common language and the values that we share,
لكن على اللغة المشتركة والقيم التي نتشاركها.
and I'm reminded of that by watching you all today.
وأنا متذكرة هذا برؤيتكم اليوم.
During my visit I've been especially honored
خلال رحلتي لقد كُرمّت خاصة
to meet some of Britain's most extraordinary women --
بلقاء بعض النساء البريطانيات غير العاديات.
women who are paving the way for all of you.
نساء يقمن بتمهيد الطريق لكم جميعاً.
And I'm honored to meet you,
ولي الشرف بلقائكم،
the future leaders of Great Britain and this world.
القادة المستقبليين لبريطانيا العظمى وهذا العالم.
And although the circumstances of our lives may seem very distant,
ورغماً عن أن ظروف حياتنا قد تبدو متباعدة جداً،
with me standing here as the First Lady of the United States of America,
معي وأنا أقف كسيدة أولى للولايات المتحدة الأمريكية،
and you, just getting through school,
وبينكم، كطالبات في المدرسة فقط.
I want you to know that we have very much in common.
أريدكم أن تعرفوا أن لدينا الكثير من القواسم المشتركة.
For nothing in my life's path
لا يوجد شئ في مسار حياتي
would have predicted that I'd be standing here
قد يتوقع أنني سأقف هنا
as the first African-American First Lady
كأول سيدة أفريقية أمريكية ، السيدة الأولى
of the United States of America.
للولايات المتحدة الامريكية.
There is nothing in my story that would land me here.
لا يوجد شئ في قصتي قد يمكنني من الوقوف هنا.
I wasn't raised with wealth or resources
لم أنُشاء بثروات أو موارد
or any social standing to speak of.
أو أي مكانة إجتماعية تذكر.
I was raised on the South Side of Chicago.
لقد ترعرعت في الجزء الجنوبي لشيكاغو.
That's the real part of Chicago.
وذلك جزء حقيقي من شيكاغو.
And I was the product of a working-class community.
وأنحدر من مجتمع طبقة عاملة.
My father was a city worker all of his life,
كان والدي عامل في المدينة طوال حياته.
and my mother was a stay-at-home mom.
وكانت والدتي ربة منزل.
And she stayed at home to take care of me and my older brother.
ولقد قعدت في البيت لتعني بي وبأخي الأكبر.
Neither of them attended university.
لم يحضر أيٌ من والدي الجامعة.
My dad was diagnosed with multiple sclerosis
تم تشخيص والدي بتصلبات متعددة
in the prime of his life.
في مقتبل عمره.
But even as it got harder for him to walk
لكن حتى بعد أن أصبح المشي صعباً له
and get dressed in the morning --
وإرتداء الملابس في الصباح --
I saw him struggle more and more --
رأيته يعاني أكثر وأكثر --
my father never complained about his struggle.
لم يشكو والدي بتاتاً من معاناته.
He was grateful for what he had.
لقد كان ممتناً لما هو عليه.
He just woke up a little earlier and worked a little harder.
لقد أستيقظ أبكر قليلاً وعمل بجد أكثر قليلاً.
And my brother and I were raised with all that you really need:
ولقد نشأنا أنا وأخي بكل ما نحتاجه حقاً:
love, strong values
الحب، القيم القوية
and a belief that with a good education
وإيمان بأن التعليم الأفضل
and a whole lot of hard work,
وكل العمل الجاد،
that there was nothing that we could not do.
هما شيئان نستطيع فعلهما.
I am an example of what's possible
أنا مثال على ماهية الشئ الممكن
when girls from the very beginning of their lives
عندما البنات من بواكير حياتهن
are loved and nurtured by the people around them.
يحاطوا بالمحبة ويترعرعوا في عناية من هم حولهم.
I was surrounded by extraordinary women in my life:
لقد أُحطت بعناية نساء إستثنائيات في حياتي.
grandmothers, teachers, aunts, cousins, neighbors,
جداتي، معلماتي، خالاتي، بنات عمومتي، جاراتي،
who taught me about quiet strength and dignity.
الذين علموني القوة والكرامة.
And my mother, the most important role model in my life,
وأمي، أهم قدوة في حياتي،
who lives with us at the White House
التي تعيش معنا في البيت الأبيض
and helps to care for our two little daughters,
وتساعدنا في الإعتناء ببنتينا الصغيرات،
Malia and Sasha.
ماليا وساشا.
She's an active presence in their lives, as well as mine,
أن لها وجود نشط في حياتهن، وكذلك حياتي،
and is instilling in them
وتغرس فيهن
the same values that she taught me and my brother:
نفس القيم التي علمتني إياها وأخي:
things like compassion, and integrity,
أشياء مثل التراحم، والنزاهة،
and confidence, and perseverance --
الثقة، والمثابرة.
all of that wrapped up in an unconditional love
وكل ذلك أُختتم بحب غير مشروط
that only a grandmother can give.
تسطيع فقط الجدة تقديمه.
I was also fortunate enough to be cherished and encouraged
أيضاً كنت محظوظة بما يكفي لأكون موضع إعتزاز وتشجيع
by some strong male role models as well,
ببعض النماذج القدوة للرجال أيضاً،
including my father, my brother, uncles and grandfathers.
ضمنهم والدي، أخي، أعمامي وجدودي.
The men in my life taught me some important things, as well.
الرجال في حياتي علموني أشياء مهمة، أيضاً.
They taught me about what a respectful relationship
لقد علموني عن كيف يجب أن تبدو العلاقة
should look like between men and women.
المحترمة بين الرجال والنساء.
They taught me about what a strong marriage feels like:
لقد علموني ماهية شعور الزواج المتماسك بشدة .
that it's built on faith and commitment
ذلك المبني على الإيمان والإلتزام
and an admiration for each other's unique gifts.
والإحترام لهدية كل طرف المتفردة.
They taught me about what it means
لقد علموني عن معنى
to be a father
أن تكون أباً
and to raise a family.
وتعتني بالأسرة.
And not only to invest in your own home
وليس فقط أن تستثمر في بيتك الخاص
but to reach out and help raise kids
بل البحث والمساعدة في تربية الأطفال
in the broader community.
في المجتمع الأوسع .
And these were the same qualities
وهذه نفس المعايير
that I looked for in my own husband,
التي أراها في زوجي،
Barack Obama.
باراك أوباما.
And when we first met,
وعندما التقينا لأول مرة
one of the things that I remember is that he took me out on a date.
أحد الأشياء التي أتذكرها هو أنه أخذني في موعد.
And his date was to go with him to a community meeting.
وموعده كان أن نذهب الى لقاء مجتمع.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I know, how romantic.
أعرف، كم هو شاعري.
But when we met, Barack was a community organizer.
لكن عندما ألتقينا، كان باراك منظّم مجتمع.
He worked, helping people to find jobs
لقد عمل، في مساعدة الناس في العثور على وظيفة
and to try to bring resources into struggling neighborhoods.
ومحاولة إيجاد موارد للأحياء التي تعاني.
As he talked to the residents in that community center,
وأثناء حديثه الى السكان في مركز المجتمع،
he talked about two concepts.
تحدث حول مفهومين.
He talked about "the world as it is" and "the world as it should be."
لقد تحدث حول" العالم كما هو" و " العالم كما ينبغي أن يكون."
And I talked about this throughout the entire campaign.
ولقد تحدثت عن هذا طوال الحملة الإنتخابية.
What he said, that all too often,
ما قاله، أنه في كثير من الأحيان،
is that we accept the distance between those two ideas.
نحن نرضى بالمسافة بين هاتين الفكرتين.
And sometimes we settle for the world as it is,
وبعض الأحيان نقبل بالعالم كما هو،
even when it doesn't reflect our values and aspirations.
حتى عندما لا يعكس قيمنا وتطلعاتنا.
But Barack reminded us on that day,
لكن باراك ذكرنا جميعاً في ذلك اليوم،
all of us in that room, that we all know
جميعنا في القاعة، أن جميعنا يعلم
what our world should look like.
كيف ينبغي لعالمنا أن يكون.
We know what fairness and justice and opportunity look like.
نحن نعرف كيف يبدو الإنصاف والعدالة والفرصة.
We all know.
نعم جميعاً.
And he urged the people in that meeting,
وقام بحثّ الناس في ذلك اللقاء،
in that community,
في ذلك المجتمع،
to devote themselves to closing the gap
لتكريس أنفسهم في ردم الهوة
between those two ideas,
بين تلك الفكرتين،
to work together to try to make the world as it is
للعمل معاً لمحاولة جعل العالم كما هو
and the world as it should be, one and the same.
والعالم كما ينبغي له، شئ واحد متطابق.
And I think about that today because I am
وأنا افكر في ذلك اليوم لأنني
reminded and convinced that all of you in this school
متذكرة ومقتنعة بأنكم جميعاً في هذه المدرسة
are very important parts of closing that gap.
أجزاء مهمة للغاية في ردم تلك الهوة.
You are the women who will build the world as it should be.
أنتن النساء اللاتي سيبنين العالم كما ينبغي له.
You're going to write the next chapter in history.
سنقوم بكتابة الفصل القادم من التاريخ.
Not just for yourselves, but for your generation
ليس فقط لأنفسكم، لكن لجيلكم
and generations to come.
والأجيال القادمة.
And that's why getting a good education
ولهذا فأن الحصول على تعليم جيد
is so important.
مهم للغاية.
That's why all of this that you're going through --
وهذا هو سبب ما تمرون به --
the ups and the downs, the teachers that you love and the teachers that you don't --
النجاحات والإخفاقات، المعلمون الذين تحبونهم والذين لا تحبونهم --
why it's so important.
هنا سبب الأهمية.
Because communities and countries and ultimately the world
لأن المجتمعات والبلدان وفي آخر المطاف العالم،
are only as strong as the health of their women.
تكمن قوته في صحة النساء.
And that's important to keep in mind.
ومن المهم وضع ذلك في الإعتبار.
Part of that health includes an outstanding education.
جزء من تلك الصحة تشمل التعليم الجيد.
The difference between a struggling family and a healthy one
الفرق بين الأسر التي تعاني والأسر الصحية
is often the presence of an empowered woman
يكمن دائماً في وجود المرأة القوية
or women at the center of that family.
أو النساء، في مركز تلك الأسرة.
The difference between a broken community and a thriving one
الفرق بين المجتمع المنكسر والمجتمع الصحي
is often the healthy respect between men and women
هو دائماً أن الصحي يحترم الفرق بين الرجال والنساء
who appreciate the contributions each other makes to society.
الذين يقدّرون مساهمات بعضهم البعض تجاه المجتمع.
The difference between a languishing nation
الفرق بين الأمة القابعة
and one that will flourish
والأمة التي تزدهر
is the recognition that we need equal access to education
هو الإعتراف بحوجتنا للحصول على فرص تعليم متساوية
for both boys and girls.
لكل من البنين والبنات .
And this school, named after the U.K.'s first female doctor,
وهذه المدرسة، سُمّيت بعد تخرج أول طبيبة إنجليزية،
and the surrounding buildings named for Mexican artist Frida Kahlo,
وسُمّيت المباني المحيطة بالفنانة المكسيكية فريدة خالو،
Mary Seacole,
ماري سيكول،
the Jamaican nurse known as the "black Florence Nightingale,"
الممرضة الجاميكية المعروفة ب "عندليبة فلورنسا السوداء،"
and the English author, Emily Bronte,
والمؤلفة الإنجليزية، إيملي برونات،
honor women who fought sexism, racism and ignorance,
تكريماً للنساء اللاتي حاربن التمييز على أساس الجنس، العنصرية والجهل،
to pursue their passions to feed their own souls.
لتلبية طموحاتهن لإشباع أرواحهن وتغذيتها.
They allowed for no obstacles.
لم تمنعنهن العقبات.
As the sign said back there, "without limitations."
وكما تقول الإشارة هناك، " بلا قيود ."
They knew no other way to live
لقد عرفن أنه لا طريق آخر للعيش
than to follow their dreams.
بدلاً عن متابعة أحلامهن.
And having done so, these women
وبعد أن حققوا ذلك، قاموا
moved many obstacles.
بإزالة الكثير من العقبات.
And they opened many new doors
ولقد فتحوا الكثير من الأبواب
for millions of female doctors and nurses
لملايين الطبيبات والممرضات
and artists and authors,
والفنانات والمؤلفات،
all of whom have followed them.
اللاتي تبعوا خطاهم.
And by getting a good education,
وبالحصول على تعليم جيد،
you too can control your own destiny.
يمكنكم أيضاً التحكم في مصائركم.
Please remember that.
رجاءً تذكروا ذلك.
If you want to know the reason why I'm standing here,
اذا أردتم معرفة سبب وقوفي هنا،
it's because of education.
فأنه بسبب التعليم.
I never cut class. Sorry, I don't know if anybody is cutting class.
لم أفوّت درساً. عذراً، لا أعرف إن كان هناك شخص يفوّت درساً.
I never did it.
لم أفعل ذلك البتة.
I loved getting As.
أحببت أن أحرز تقدير ممتاز.
I liked being smart.
أحببت أن أكون ذكية.
I liked being on time. I liked getting my work done.
أحببت أن أحافظ على الوقت. أحببت أن أنجز عملي.
I thought being smart was cooler than anything in the world.
أعتقدت أنه لتصبح ذكياً هو أفضل من أي شئ في العالم.
And you too, with these same values,
وأنتم أيضاً، بنفس هذه القيم،
can control your own destiny.
يمكنكم التحكم في مصائركم.
You too can pave the way.
أنتم أيضاً يمكنكم تمهيد الطريق.
You too can realize your dreams,
ويمكنكم أيضاً تحقيق أحلامكم،
and then your job is to reach back
وبعد ذلك فأن واجبكم هو التواصل
and to help someone just like you do the same thing.
ومساعدة شخص ما مثلكم في أن يفعل نفس الشئ.
History proves that it doesn't matter
يثبت التاريخ أنه لا يهم
whether you come from a council estate
سواء أتيت من مجلس ولاية
or a country estate.
أو مجلس ريفي.
Your success will be determined
نجاحك سيتم تحديده
by your own fortitude,
بثباتكم الخاص،
your own confidence, your own individual hard work.
بثقتكم أنتم، عملكم الفردي الجاد.
That is true. That is the reality of the world that we live in.
ذلك صحيح. تلك هي حقيقة العالم الذي نعيش فيه.
You now have control over your own destiny.
لديكم الآن إمكانية التحكم في مصائركم.
And it won't be easy -- that's for sure.
ولن يكون هذا سهلاً. هذا مؤكد.
But you have everything you need.
لكن لديكم كل شئ تحتاجونه.
Everything you need to succeed,
كل شئ تحتاجونه لتنجحوا،
you already have, right here.
لديكم بالفعل حقوق هنا.
My husband works in this big office.
زوجي يعمل في هذا المكتب الكبير.
They call it the Oval Office.
يسمونه بالمكتب البيضاوي.
In the White House, there's the desk that he sits at --
في البيت الأبيض، هناك المكتب الذي يجلس عليه.
it's called the Resolute desk.
يسمى المكتب الحازم.
It was built by the timber of Her Majesty's Ship Resolute
لقد بُني من أخشاب سفينة صاحبة الجلالة حازمة
and given by Queen Victoria.
وقدمته الملكة فيكتوريا.
It's an enduring symbol of the friendship between our two nations.
أنه رمز دائم للعلاقة بين الأمتين.
And its name, Resolute,
وأسمه، الحازم،
is a reminder of the strength of character that's required
هو تذكير بقوة الشخصية المطلوبة
not only to lead a country,
ليس فقط لقيادة البلاد،
but to live a life of purpose, as well.
لكن لتعيش حياة بهدف، أيضاً.
And I hope in pursuing your dreams, you all remain resolute,
وأتمنى في تحقيق أحلامكم، أن تظلوا حازمين،
that you go forward without limits,
بأنكم ستمضوا قدماً بدون قيود،
and that you use your talents -- because there are many; we've seen them;
وأنكم ستستخدمون مواهبكم -- لأنها متعددة. لقد رأيناها.
it's there --
أنها موجودة.
that you use them to create the world as it should be.
أن تستخدموها لصنع العالم كما ينبغي له.
Because we are counting on you.
لأننا نعوّل عليكم.
We are counting on every single one of you
أننا نعوّل على أي فرد منكم
to be the very best that you can be.
لتصبح أفضل ما تستطيع أن تكون.
Because the world is big.
لأن العالم كبير.
And it's full of challenges.
وملئ بالتحديات.
And we need strong, smart, confident young women
ونحن نريد شابات قويات، أذكياء واثقات من أنفسهن
to stand up and take the reins.
للوقوف وتولي زمام السلطة.
We know you can do it. We love you. Thank you so much.
نعلم أنه يمكنكم فعلها. نحن نحبكم. شكراً جزيلاً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)